# Justo O. Ochung'

Science Educator & Youths' Advocate

Email: kochungjusto26@gmail.com, Phone No: +254-799-762-744 https://www.linkedin.com/in/justo-ochung-a038a260/

# **Professional Summary**

I have a cumulative of 7 years teaching experience at Primary, Secondary, and Tertiary levels in remote and urban regions in Kenya. I am experienced in both remote and physical teaching and academic administration to learners at all levels or ethic/racial associations. I am also a skilled research writer spanning over 8 years, data manager and analyst, and digital leader competent in transformational leadership and communication. I am currently pursuing an opportunity that will encourage the development of a contemporary science/technical curricula for solving future skillsgap especially leading to self-employment amongst youths.

#### **Skills**

Git | SQL | Python | Collaboration | R Programming | Flask | Linux | | Communication | Curriculum Development | Academic Administration | Student Leadership | Technical Leadership | Report Writing | Transformational Leadership

# **Educational Background**

#### Post Graduate Diploma in Education

2021-2023

KCA University
Communication, Administration, Leadership,
Teaching

#### **Software Programming**

2020-2020

Moringa School
HTML, CSS3, Git, Python, Flask, Angular,
JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, R

#### MSc. Molecular Medicine

2017-

JKUAT/KEMRI ITROMID
Scientific Research & Communication. (

Scientific Research & Communication, Collaboration, Data Mining & Analysis

### **BSc.** Biochemistry

2010-2014

Kenyatta University Scientific Skills, Creativity, Leadership

# Work Experience

Freelance Software Developer & Technical Writer	2021- Present
<ul> <li>Technical writing on emerging issues in software design,</li> </ul>	
development, and implementation.	
Web design and development	
Collaborating in software projects and students' advising	

T 1 1777 *.	2047 B
Freelance Writer	2016- Present
Upwork Inc.	
• Advising learners on academic writing, thesis development and writing, and	
2016 – Present term paper writings	
Writing admission and scholarship essays for talented students looking for	
opportunities in world-class universities/institutions	
Delivering technical and topic-based presentations based on students'	
learning needs	
• Writing literature reviews and issue-based research as requested by clients	
Offered career guidance and counselling to prospective students looking	
for professional studies oversees	
Early Research Scientist & Committee Member	2023- Present
Kenya Medical Research Institute Graduate School	2023 1163611
Roles	
Identifying grant calls and collaborating for applications	
Drafting Literature reviews, editing, and managing the grant writing	
process	
Submission of grant proposals in collaboration with the	
Grants committee	
Mentoring students in science writing & communication	
racing students in science withing to communication	
Lecturer (Intern)	2022-2022
Thika Technical Training Institute	
Roles	
Taught & assessed Biochemistry and Research Methods units	
Collaborated with the science department in organizing biochemistry	
laboratory workshops for students	
Prepared lecturer notes and assessment manuals	
Assisted applied science department (teachers & students) in digital	
on-boarding for the online classes and assessments	
Underwent Institution's organized training sessions on Teacher  Prof. 1. D. 1. 1. 1. 1. 1. 1. 1. 1. 1. 1. 1. 1. 1.	
Professional Development	
Director of Studies and Science Teacher	2010-1014 (During
Ngutu Mixed Secondary School	May-August
Roles;	University Holidays)
• Formulated teaching designs and assessments for science and non-science	
subjects through collaboration with teachers and learners	
Oversaw the administration of examinations and teaching calendar on	
behalf of the school leadership	
• Directed laboratory practical learning syllabus and initiated the hiring of an	
experienced laboratory technician	
Collaborated with neighboring schools for academic competitions,	
especially in the sciences	
• Assisted in the administration of learners' and teachers' discipline through	
collaboration with teachers, administration, community members, and	
government officials	

• Organized science workshops, joint district examinations, and conferences	
on behalf of the school for teachers and students	
• Administered student affairs and addressing them based on school needs	
through association with the administration, parents, and teachers	
Primary School Teacher	2009-2010
St. Alekia Primary School	
Roles;	
- Taught Science and Kiswahili subjects Class 4, 7, and 8 students	
- Worked alongside students' and teachers' leadership to create a	
successful science club	
- Organized teachers' joint administration and assessment of	
examinations for science and technical subjects	
- Organized academic days for students, parents and teachers'	
discussion forums	
- Worked alongside Plan International to assist vulnerable students in	
meeting their school financial needs.	

## **REFEREES**

Dr. Florence Kinyua Grants Committee Secretariat KEMRI Graduate School Mobile No: +254725237625 Email:

flokinyua2012@gmail.com

Godfrey Wachira Lecturer, Thika Technical Training Institute Mobile: +254 720 217522 Email:wachirakimotho25@gmail.com Dr. Victor O. Oria (Ph.D.), Post-Doc Fellow, Biotech Research & Innovation Centre (BRIC), The University of Copenhagen, Mobile No: +4550166896 Email: voria87@gmail.com